Hello, all my friends, and welcome again to the complete data structure and then good ethics course
in this exercise number 47, we are asked to write the function to get the count of notes and link at
last.
So how to get the count of the notes in the link, at least iteratively and recursively.
So we need to create both.
If both parties using a third iteration and using that recursion.
So all the video and think about it, how to get this the count of the nodes in the linked list, using
iteration and using recursive.
By the way, we have created these methods for the linked list and we are making a new data structure.
So think about it as a developer in an oracle and you are creating a new data structure called linkage
list without inventing without its invention.
So this is how we think about data structure.
OK, now I need from you to copy these exercises and write them down in your notebook because they are
very important for your interview and your university subjects related to data structure and algorithms.
So start public and get count.
OK.
It's void and it's sorted.
It returns an end, and it does not take any parameters.
So because we didn't deal with that nuts, we're stuck.
This is the iterative we have.
This is not the time to be equal, to had to refer to the hat and count equal to zero.
We start by you.
We have seen this exercise in the lecture before, so please go back to the lectures and see how to
make this happen.
And using the C and Java and we have solved like this exercise.
The trick here is to create a new variable called count and an every iteration increase count by one
count plus plus and that move the cursor to then next time.
So temp the next game, we are moving the cursor to that next day and then return and count because
it will return the.
Integer.
OK.
It's very simple, because we have created it.
This is why loop and we have increased count and every time stamp does not equal to null.
So when Stamp, which is referring to that pointer, the next nod does not equal to null.
So when we reach stamp equal to null, then we reach the end of the link at less, then return that
count a breakthrough and return that count.
Let's run and see and this example.
OK.
Exercise number forty two, forty.
Sorry.
Forty seven, I think.
OK, get count of knots.
So system that out dot, print and link atlas dot get count.
It's very simple.
Let's run.
Here we go.
We have.
I let me put this the count.
Let's run and see again.
Four, one, five and three, the count of these nods are thought.
OK.
So it's working fine, and we are making it as it correctly by creating this get count of known if they're
relatively OK.
Now, let's solve the same exercise.
But in Eric Recursion.
OK, I will create this recursive function.
It will call and get count, but recursive recursive OK.
When using the recursion, we need to make a method that the parameter so it took parameter of time.
No.
OK.
So this is the base case base case, if not equal, equal to null, then return zero.
It's very simple because we are making and breaking the not equal equal to null, then return zero.
Otherwise, this will count.
Count this count.
Is this not plus rest of count?
This not this node class, rest of the rest of the list.
OK.
How to do that return one plus again, we we call the method because it's recursive.
You count and not dot next.
OK.
This is how we make this happens in the recursion.
I need to make and, you know, a new method called public.
Or you can pass the hat.
OK?
You can pass the hat whenever you called this so public and get count recursively is the base case that
will break from the loop or from the recursively recursion.
We have seen that we need to make a condition that breaks the recursion.
So this is the base case.
This is the case that we have to break from the recursion.
It's not equal, equal to none.
Otherwise, it will count return one plus get count recursively.
It will call this again by passing not dot next and so on, until reaching not equal to none.
Let's see if this method, how it works.
So again, I will copy this.
The count recursively recursively would equal to link at least get it count recursively, and I need
to pass there.
Not so what what I'm doing here.
I need to pass that link Atlas Dot hat I am testing starting from the head and tail reaching the end
of that list.
And let's see.
Here we go.
We have four nodes that count using the iteration is four.
And the count recursively is four.
And it's working fine.
Both methods works and give us the same results.
OK.
So this is about this exercise for these seven getting the count of nodes iteratively and and a recursive
recursively.
OK.
So I am waiting.
Your questions, exercises and solutions.
Any recommendation or any suggestion for new tutorials and new exercises or any any doubt that you may
have?
Please comment below.
And I am here.